hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says four consecutive positive even
integers have a product of 13440 what
are the integers so it means something
like 2 * 4 * 6 * 8 or 4 * 6 * 8 * 10
there are some four consecutive even
integers that multiply to 13440 we could
just keep guessing and checking and
trying more and more of these but I want
to see if we can do it algebraically if
you want to try it on your own pause it
right now cuz I'm going to solve it in 3
2 1 let's call the first even integer X
so the next even integer will have to be
two more than that so it' be x + 2 and
then we do the same thing to get the
next two integers and we need these to
multiply to
13440 next if we multiply all these out
it's going to take us a while and it
will give us this right here and then we
can subtract 13440 from both sides and
we get all of this equal to zero this
can be solved but it'll take quite a bit
of work let me show you a shortcut
instead of having the four terms be
these let's have them be these right
here they're all still two apart from
each other so these are four consecutive
even integers they're just expressed a
little bit differently and if we
rearrange them like this then we have a
difference of two squares and another
difference of two squares so x + 1 * x
-1 is just x^2 - 1 and then x - 3 * x +
3 is just x^2 - 9 and then multiplying
these out is significantly easier than
multiplying this out x^2 * x^2 is x 4 X2
* 9 is 9x2 -1 * x^2 is -1 x^2 and-1 * 9
is POS 9 we can combine like terms this
9 x^2 - 1 x^2 will become -10 x^2 and
then we can subtract 13440 from both
sides and we end up with x 4 - 10 x^2 -
13431 = 0 this is significantly easier
than this we can factor out this left
hand side we need two numbers that add
to -10 and multiply to -3 431 this will
take a little bit of trial and error but
that ends up being -21 and POS 111 and
then x^2 - 121 is another difference of
two squares that gives us x - 11 * x +
11 and then we can just copy down the
rest of this stuff and now that we have
this factored we can solve for each of
these for x^2 + 11 = 0 we can subtract
11 from both sides that'll give us x^2 =
-11 and that has two imaginary Solutions
plus or minus IUN 11 after we plug this
in up here and subtract three it will
not give us an even integer so this is
not a valid solution and then for x + 11
we can subtract 11 from both sides and
we get x = -1 11 that won't give us a
positive even integer so that is also
not a valid solution and then for the
last one x - 11 if we add 11 to both
sides we get x = 11 and x = 11 will work
for us so let's copy these down and
let's plug in 11 into each of the x's
and that gives us 11 - 3 which is 8 11 -
1 which is 10 11 + 1 which is 12 and 11
+ 3 which is 14 and these are our four
consecutive positive even integers let's
put a box around them how exciting